# Hae-Yeon, Hwang

112-1203, 56, Digital-ro Gwangmyeong-si, Gyeonggi-do, 14242 +82 10 2936 8514 haeyun@gmail.com

# Summary

Passionate IT engineer and technical executive director with 23+ year of experience and a proven track record in software and hardware development.

Exceptional communicator with a consultative business style, exceptional problem solving abilities.

Aggressively identify opportunities, develop focus, and catch-up a tactical business moments.

## Education

**Inha University** *Bechelor of Science in Computer Engineering* 

Incheon, Incheon Graduated February 1997

# **Employment History**

MNL Solution
Executive Director, CTO

Seoul, Seoul August 2012 - September 2018

Responsible for overall business development and technical leading for R&D Group as a CTO.

Responsible for creating new business opportunities with technologies and market harmonized. (like a 5G/NFV/SDN, augmented reality, Hadoop/Splunk/ELK, Cloud computing (AWS, Azure, Openstack/Cloudstack).

- business development for LTE/5G (KT private LTE, 5G E2E orchestrator)
- accomplished government project as a PM (MSIT pyeongchang olympic 2018, NIPA/KISA strategy report for paperless e-receipt, MSIT smart home IoT/cloud, MSS federation for heterogeneous cloud computing, KISA converging service for future internet, NIA standard for cctv infrastructure
- development software and deploy service (LGU+ IoT video/streaming platform a.k.a. "MomCa", home cctv, lte blackbox, lte drone, LGE smart tv accelerator server)
- business development for mobile boundaries (SEC mobile Instance messaging a.k.a. "ChatON", recommendation service/ML, SEC health care, SKT location based service, contents management service)

#### Customer:

- manufacture: SEC (samsung electronics), LGE (LG electronics)
- carrier: KT (korea telecom), SKT (sk telecom), LGU+ (LG uplus), SK planet, SK broadband
- retails: AP (amore pacific)
- System Integration: HP, SDS, LG-CNS, LDCC (Lotte data communication company)
- advertisement: CHEIL worldwide, Pengtai
- government: KISA (Korea Internet Security Agency), MSS (Ministry of Science and ICT), KCC (Korea Communications Commission), NIA (National Information Society Agency), NIPA (National IT Industry Promotion Agency), MSIT (Ministry of Science and ICT), MSS (Ministry of SMEs and Startups)

uPRESTO Seoul, Seoul

Responsible for overall business development and technical leading for R&D Group as a CTO.

and making business strategy and planning.

- business and system development for "performance assurance service" (2G WAP, 3G CDMA/EVDO, WCDMA, WiMax/WiBro)
- software development for packet analyzer (KT, LGU+ for mobile infrastructure traffic analysis; TCP/IP, HTTP, SS7/Sigtran, SMS/MMS, ...)
- business development for charging/billing gateway (KT CDMA/WCDMA, LGU+ CDMA)
- oversea business for above solution (Canada Bell mobility, Telus, Rogers, Malaysia YTL, US Metro PCS)
- government project as a PM (dlna for home appliance, digital signage)

#### Customer:

- carrier: SKT (sk telecom), KT (korea telecom), LGU+ (LG uplus), Canada Bell mobility, Telus, Rogers
- manufacture: SEC (Samsung electronics)
- government: KISA (Korea Internet Security Agency), MSIT (Ministry of Science and ICT), KCC (Korea Communications Commission)

**Eluon**Senior Staff / Software Engineer

Seoul, Seoul

July 2000 - December 2005

Responsible for development core system for carrier-grade. (KT, SKT, LGU+)

- imt-2000 core system development (sgsn/ggsn/ha)
- advanced dual-stack packet gateway development (pdsn & ggsn)
- signaling gateway development
- embedding ipv6 kernel feature at packet gateway development
- carrier grade oss/bss development
- adaptive memoty database interface module development (oracle timesten/altibase/memcached)
- feasibility study and proposal for overseas telecom (virtualized switch and gateway; japan/kddi and docomo)

#### Customer:

• carrier: KT (korea telecom), LGU+ (LG uplus)

## LG Electronics

Seoul, Seoul

Senior / Software Engineer

January 1997 - June 2000

Responsible for software development of dial-up internet(a.k.a. "KT 014XY")

• part leader for o&am and high-performance connectivity module, forming a consortium with samsung electronics, daewoo. (langauge; c/c++ & informix/oracle)

### Customer:

• carrier: KT (korea telecom)

# **Hobbies & Interests**

Pay attention to the new trends and technologies

- IoT (embedded OS, connectivity, streaming, IoT platform, CAD/3D/board model)
- Deep learning (tensorflow/keras/kaggle)
- Blockchain (Hyperledger, Ethereum)

- cloud computing and deploy (aws, azure, gcp, pelion, heroku, k8s)
- mobile platform (android/ios, kotlin, tizen)

and "Makers" activities

• makes a smart mirror, smart weather station, internet radio/speaker, arcade box and so on and like brewering korean traditional liquor

## Awards

- Seoul hardware hackathon / IoT (Excellence award, Mar 2019)
- DMC innovation camp, startup challenge (Encouragement prize, Nov 2018)
- Smartmedia, startup challenge (Encouragement prize, Nov 2018)

## Professional Skills

C/C++	****
Embedded OS	****
IoT	****
IT Infrastructure	****
Cloud computing	$\star\star\star\star\star$
Streaming	****

# Languages

English Conversational